calcpa.org 2014-12-10

# Privacy Policy

| 

## California Society of CPAs' Online Privacy Policy Statement

[www.calcpa.org](http://www.calcpa.org/) is a website ("the Site") of the California Society of Certified Public Accountants ("CalCPA") and CPA Education Foundation. CalCPA is committed to maintaining your confidence and trust. We understand the value of your personal information and we respect your right to restrict our use of it. CalCPA has created this Online Privacy Policy Statement ("the Privacy Policy") to demonstrate our commitment to fair information practices and the protection of privacy. 

###### **1\. Access to the Areas of Our Web Site.**

Our Site has areas that are open to all users, with no registration required to obtain access. 

Some areas of our Site, including specific pages in the "for Members" section are password-protected for specific user groups, such as Members of CalCPA ("Members"). CalCPA disseminates a user name and password to each member of these user groups; no online registration is required. Membership in CalCPA is required to access these areas. 

###### **2\. Information We Collect.**

  * **Web site Usage Information** Collected. Our Web server automatically collects and aggregates information about your visit to our Site, including your service provider, browser type, domain names of referring web sites, the pages accessed on our Site, and the date and time of your access. This is anonymous information that does not personally identify you **.**

  * **Personal Information Collected.** When you use our Site's "Contact Us" feature, fill out a form, submit a classified ad, complete a survey or poll on our Site or access subscription or Customer services that we offer through our Site, you will give us information that personally identifies you. Personal information may include: (i) contact data (such as your name, mailing and e-mail addresses and telephone numbers); (ii) financial data (such as your account number); and (iii) demographic data (such as your zip code, age, or affiliations). If you communicate with us by e-mail, post any information or messages to any job listing area, chat groups, bulletin boards or other facilities that may exist on our Site from time to time, post a classified advertisement, or complete online forms, surveys, polls or contest entries, we may collect any information from that communication. **  
**

  * **Automatic Information Collected.** We automatically send, receive and store the information about your visit to our Site described in Section 2.a. above. Unlike many other websites which use "cookies" to provide information about you, the only cookie we use on our Site is one to automatically remember Member logins and passwords for the password-protected areas. **  
**

  * **Information from Other Sources.** We only collect information from you and from returned mail, not from outside sources. **  
**

###### **3\. Use of Information We Collect.**

We will store and update the contact information, demographic information and other information collected from Members.

We also may use Web site usage information and personal information for editorial and feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes, for statistical analyses of user behavior, for product development, for content improvement, to inform advertisers how many visitors have seen or clicked on their advertisements, and to customize the content and layout of our Site. Personal information, including names, postal and e-mail addresses and phone numbers, may be added to our databases and used in the following ways:

  * to contact you when necessary. 
  * to fulfill your requests and process your transactions. 
  * to respond to your e-mail messages. 
  * to attempt to optimize your experience and enhance your time spent with us online.

###### 4\. Sharing and Release of Information We Collect.

We share website usage information, demographic data, automatically collected data, and feedback with partners, advertisers and other third parties only on an aggregate basis.

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling subscriptions and orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing and/or sales assistance, providing customer service for our Site, evaluating enrollment applications and carrying out duties in the operation of our programs. These third parties have access to Web site usage information, contact information, demographic information, automatically collected information and feedback needed to perform their functions, but they may not use it for other purposes.

As CalCPA continues to grow, we might sell or buy sites, companies or assets. In such transactions, Web site usage information and personal information generally is one of the transferred business assets.

We will, without specific or further notice to you, release your Web site usage information, contact information, demographic information, automatically collected data and feedback when we believe such disclosure is appropriate to: (a) comply with any law or a court order or other legal process; (b) protect the rights, property or safety of CalCPA, our Site, our Members, our visitors, enrollees in our programs, our employees, contractors, agents or others; or (c) enforce our terms of service. ****

###### **5\. Security.**

We work to include security measures in this Site to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information within our control that you provide to us. However, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of that information. It also is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer or one that is otherwise accessible to third parties. ****

###### **6\. User Ability to Access, Update and Correct Personal Information.**

To ensure that all of your Personal Information is correct and up-to-date, you may visit your personal profile at [www.calcpa.org/find](http://www.calcpa.org/find). Through your personal profile you may: (a) review and update your Personal Information that we have already collected; (b) choose whether or not you wish us to send you information about us, or promotional material from some of our partners; and (c) choose whether or not you wish us to share some of your Personal Information with third parties. ****

###### **7\. Lost or Stolen Information.**

You must promptly notify us if your user name or password is lost, stolen or used without permission. In such an event, we will cancel that user name or password and update our records accordingly. ****

###### **8\. Public Forums.**

Our Site may make chat rooms, job listing areas, forum facilities, message boards, e-groups, news groups and similar features available to you. Please understand that any information that you disclose in these areas becomes public information and that we have no control over its use. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information or any other information about yourself. In addition, the thoughts expressed in these areas reflect the views of the individual users or hosts and do not necessarily reflect the views of CalCPA or any of its affiliates. ****

###### **9\. Updates and Changes to Privacy Policy.**

This Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions of Use may change frequently, and use of information that we gather now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of use. We reserve the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such change, update or modification on our Site. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on our Site. You should check our Site frequently, and the page where this Privacy Policy is posted, to see recent changes. **  
**

###### ****10\. Conditions of Use.

By using our Site, you consent to the collection and use of information described above. Your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions of Use, including limitations on damages and the application of the law of the State of California. If you have any concern about privacy at our Site, please send a detailed message to us at [info@calcpa.org](mailto:info@calcpa.org), and we will try to resolve it. **  
**

###### **11\. Opt Out Process.**

We make every effort to contact you only if you have previously chosen to receive communications from us. At any time, you can "opt out" of receiving direct mail and marketing material from CalCPA, such as product and service updates, by e-mailing us at [info@calcpa.org](mailto:info@calcpa.org) or calling (800) 922-5272. If you do not want us to share your personal information with any third parties, please e-mail us at [info@calcpa.org](mailto:info@calcpa.org) or call (800) 922-5272. 

If, at any time in the future, we decide to use your personal information for a purpose not currently stated in this Policy, we will modify the Policy to disclose such usage. In addition, we will provide you with the opportunity and ability to opt out of this new use. **  
**

###### **12\. Links to Other Websites.**

Our Site contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. You are encouraged to become familiar with the privacy policies and practices of every Web site that you visit prior to disclosing any personal information. **  
**

###### **13\. Security of Personal Information.**

We store your personal information in a secure location that is accessible only by designated staff. We make reasonable efforts to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction. In addition, we use a secure server to protect the safety and security of transactions over the Internet involving personal information. **  
**

###### **14.  Acceptance.**

By using [www.calcpa.org](http://www.calcpa.org/), you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time. If you do not agree with the terms and conditions contained in this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Site. **  
**

###### **15\. Contact Us.**

If you have thoughts, questions or suggestions about this Privacy Policy or any other aspect of your relationship with CalCPA, please contact us. 

Our postal address is as follows: 

California Society of CPAs  
Attn: Customer Services  
1800 Gateway Drive, Ste 200  
San Mateo, California 94404-4072

We can be reached via e-mail at [info@calcpa.org](mailto:info@calcpa.org)

Or you can reach us by telephone at (800) 922-5272.
